叫醒美国佬
嘿
Hey!
国家歌剧院
我们活在一个暮光世界
We live in a twilight world.
且黄昏时没有朋友
And there are no friends at dusk.
你的身分曝光 这场突袭是为了消灭你
You've been made. This siege is a blind for them to vanish you.
但我建立了联系
But I established contact.
带你走或杀了你 我只有两分钟 快做决定
Bring you in or kill you. I have two minutes. Make up your mind.
东西在哪里
Where's the package?
衣帽间
Coat check.
待在这里
Stay.
拿他的
你在干嘛
你是谁
黄昏时没有朋友
No friends at dusk, huh?
有你就行 带他到集合点
You'll do. Get him to the rally point.
换衣服 乌克兰人等的是一名乘客
Swap clothes. The Ukrainians are expecting a passenger.
我从没看过这种容器
I've never seen encapsulation like this.
不知道有多古老 但是货真价实
We don't know how old it is, but it's the real deal.
有逃脱备案吗
Did you have an out?
通往下水道的施工隧道
Service tunnel to the sewer.
拿去 带他走他的出口 我不信任我们的人
Take this. Take him. Take his exit. I don't trust ours anymore.
能拆除炸弹吗
Can you defuse that?
那会同步引爆 还有更多吗
They're centrally synchronized. Are there more?
这可以掩盖他们的踪迹
Covering their tracks.
-连观众都炸  -它们只是廉价的位子
- Taking out the audience? - They're just the cheap seats.
快走吧
Walk away.
你不必杀死这些人
You don't have to kill these people.
-他不是我们的人 -我需要帮手
That wasn't one of us. I'll take the help.
快走 快走
Go, go, go.
不是那家伙
人在受训后 撑得住18小时刑求
A man can be trained to hold out for about 18 hours,
所以你的同僚7点后就安全了
so your colleagues will be clear by 7:00.
他连18分钟都撑不住
He didn't last 18 minutes.
他没什么好隐瞒了
He didn't have anything to hide.
你救出个无名小卒
You were smuggling a nobody.
风险很大
It's risky.
还是你指望这玩意
Or were you counting on this?
自杀药丸 中情局标配
Death. CIA issue.
他们一旦安全就让自己活命
Spare yourself, once they clear.
就快7点了 糟糕
Almost 7:00. Uh-oh.
时钟跑太快
It's running fast.
我得拨慢一小时
We have to put it back one hour.
吐出来
Get it out!
欢迎来到来世
Welcome to the afterlife.
你陷入人工昏迷期间
You've been in a medically-induced coma
我们把你救出来 重建你的口腔
while we got you out of Ukraine and rebuilt your mouth.
自杀药丸是假的
The suicide pills are fake.
为什么
Why?
这是个考验
A test.
考验
A test?
他们拔光我的牙齿
They pulled my teeth out.
小队安全逃走了吗
Did my team get clear?
没有 可能是俄罗斯佣兵干的
No. Private Russians, we think.
有人招供
Somebody talked.
你没有
Not you.
你宁死也不愿放弃同僚
You chose to die instead of giving up your colleagues.
我们都相信自己会冲进火场
We all believe we'd run into the burning building.
直到感受到热浪
But until we feel that heat,
谁也不能确定 但你能
we can never know.You do.
我辞职
I resign.
你不替我们做事 你已经死了
You don't work for us. You're dead.
你的职责超越国家利益
Your duty transcends national interests.
这是为了人类存亡
This is about survival.
谁的
Whose?
所有人
Everyone's.
这是一场冷酷无情的冷战
There's a cold war, cold as ice.
只要知道它的本质就会输
To even know its true nature is to lose.
天机不可泄漏
This is knowledge divided.
我只能给你一个手势 加上一个字
All I have for you is a gesture in combination with a word.
天能
"Tenet."
小心运用
Use it carefully.
它能开启正确的门 也会打开错误的门
It'll open the right doors, but some of the wrong ones, too.
他们只告诉你这些
That's all they've told you?
你通过的考验
That test you passed?
不是每个人都能通过
Not everybody does.
爱西尼号
启动
B-2室
穿上反光背心 拿着笔记板 几乎就能闯入任何地方
With a high-vis vest and a clipboard, you can get almost anywhere.
几乎啦
Almost.
谜一般的天能
An obscure tenet.
别闲聊 别曝露我们的身分和目的
No small talk. Nothing that might reveal who we are or what we do.
我以为我是来找出任务目的
I thought I was here to find out what we do.
你不必知道 只要学会
You're not here for "what," you're here for "how."
那是你的任务 与我无关
"What" is your department and not my business.
为了执行任务
Well, to do what I do...
我需要知道面对什么威胁
I need some idea of the threat we face.
以我的了解 我们试图阻止第三次世界大战
As I understand it, we're trying to prevent World War III.
核战
Nuclear holocaust?
不
No.
更糟的事
Something worse.
瞄准后开枪
Aim it and pull the trigger.
弹匣是空的
It's empty.
瞄准
Aim it.
检查弹匣
Check the magazine.
怎么会
How?
其中一颗子弹和我们一样 顺着时间向前进
One of these bullets is like us, traveling forwards through time.
另一颗则是向后退
The other one's going backwards.
分得出来吗
Can you tell which is which?
现在呢 完全逆转
How about now?
熵造成反向运作 让动作看起来全都倒转
It's inverted. Its entropy runs backwards. So, to our eyes, its movement is reversed.
可能是核分裂引发的反向辐射
We think it's a type of inverse radiation triggered by nuclear fission.
-不是你制造的  -我们还不知道怎么做
You didn't make it?
有人在未来制造 然后逆转时间传送给我们
Someone's manufacturing them in the future. They're streaming back at us.
试试看
Try it.
你要想着放下子弹
You have to have dropped it.
我还没碰 它怎么会动
How can it move before I touch it?
从你的角度是你抓住子弹
From your point of view, you caught it.
从子弹的角度是你放下它
But from the bullet's point of view, you dropped it.
但原因应该先于结果
But cause comes before effect.
不 那是我们看待时间的方法
No, that's just the way we see time.
自由意志呢
Well, what about free will?
你不出手 那颗子弹就不会动
That bullet wouldn't have moved if you hadn't put your hand there.
不管怎么看 都是你造成的
Either way we run the tape, you made it happen.
别试着理解它
Don't try to understand it.
感受它
Feel it.
直觉
Instinct.
我懂了
Got it.
为何感觉这么奇怪
Why does it feel so strange?
你不是射出子弹 而是接住它
You're not shooting the bullet, you're catching it.
哇塞
Whoa.
我看过这种子弹
I've seen this type of ammunition before.
出任务时
In the field?
我差点被打中
I was almost hit.
那你很幸运
Then you were exceedingly lucky.
被逆转的子弹打中会受重伤 下场很惨
An inverted bullet passing through your body would be devastating. Not pretty.
这些像是现代的子弹
These look like today's.
可能是现在制造 却在多年后被逆转
They may have been made today and inverted years from now.
从哪弄来的
Where did you get them?
墙上挖出来的 我奉命研究这里所有的物质
Came with the wall. I was assigned it, like all the material I'm studying here.
分析过金属成分吗
Do you have an analysis on the metals?
当然了 怎么了
Sure. Why?
混合哪些合金我也许能辨识 是在哪里制造 听好
The mixture of alloys can tell me where they might have been made. Look...
这不是世界末日
I'm not seeing Armageddon here.
子弹看似普通 但却是一台简单机器
The bullet may not seem like much, but it's a simple machine.
铅弹头 铜弹壳 火药
Lead bullet, brass casing, gunpowder.
他们能逆转子弹就能逆转任何东西
If they can invert that, I see no reason they couldn't invert pretty much anything.
一枚核弹只能危害人类未来
Even a nuclear weapon can only affect our future.
但逆转时间的武器却能毁灭这世界
An inverted weapon might be able to affect our past as well.
既然已经知道这种科技 就能找到更多逆转的物质
Now that we know what to look for, we're finding more and more inverted material.
更复杂的残余物
Remnants of complex objects.
你觉得这些是什么
What do you think we're seeing?
即将来临的战争废墟
The detritus of a coming war.
-喂  -我们活在一个暮光世界
- Yep? - We live in a twilight world.
黄昏时没有朋友 我听说你死了
No friends at dusk. I was told you left the building.
就连死人也需要盟友
Even the dead need allies.
什么盟友
Specifically?
我在孟买需要帮手找到桑杰辛格
I need an assist in Mumbai. I need to get to Sanjay Singh.
辛格 他足不出户 他家
Singh? He never leaves his house. And his house is...
-很高 -没错 我看到了
- his house. - Yes, it is.
两小时后孟买游艇俱乐部见
Bombay Yacht Club in two hours.
看来你临时需要人介绍 一位有威望的孟买当地人士
It seems you need an introduction to a prominent Mumbai local on short notice.
-我是尼尔 -我想见桑杰辛格
I'm Neil. I need an audience with Sanjay Singh.
不可能
That's not possible.
最多10分钟
Ten minutes tops.
问题不是时间
Time isn't the problem.
而是能不能活着出来
It's getting out alive that's the problem.
你会胁持小孩或女人当人质吗
Would you take a child hostage? A woman?
有必要的话 我不想要惹麻烦
If I had to. I'm not looking to make much noise here.
点什么
Yes?
伏特加通宁和健怡可乐
Vodka tonic. And a Diet Coke.
怎么了
What?
-你出任务时不喝酒 -知道就好
You never drink on the job. You're well-informed.
这是干我们这一行的好处
Well, pays to be in our profession.
我宁愿喝苏打水
Well, I prefer soda water.
才怪
No, you don't.
你的跳伞技术怎样
How's your parachuting?
受训时摔断过脚踝
I broke an ankle during basic training.
辛格的房子不够高 不能跳伞
Singh's house isn't tall enough to parachute off of.
-但具有高空弹跳性 -高空弹跳性不算个词
It's bungee-jumpable. I don't think "bungee-jumpable" is a word.
也许不是 但那是唯一逃脱的方法
It may not be a word, but it may be our only way out of that place.
或是闯进去的方法
Or into it, for that matter.
我知道你累了 我也很累
I know you're tired. I'm also very tired.
退后
Stay back.
我在乌克兰差点被一种 非比寻常的子弹射死
I was almost taken out by a very unusual type of ammunition in Ukraine.
我想知道是谁给的
I want to know who supplied it.
我是桑杰 你是
My name is Sanjay. And you are?
不想闲聊
No chitchat?
不会有人回应 也没人会来救你
There's no one at the other end. No one who's gonna help you, anyway.
别让食物凉掉
Don't let it get cold.
我怎么知道是谁给的
Why should I know who supplied it?
金属成分只有印度才有
The combination of metals is unique to India.
如果来自印度  那就是你给的
If it's from India, it's from you.
那么  扣钱吧
Deduction, then.
我不是被派来谈判的
I'm not the man they send to negotiate.
也不是来跟你交易
Or the man they send to make deals.
但有事大家都来找我
But I am the man people talk to.
不行 我不能告诉你
I can't.
泄漏客户的机密
This may be the easiest trigger I've ever had to pull.
会违反他奉为准则的教条
To say anything about a client would violate the tenets he lives by.
如果你这么重视教条
If tenets are important to you,
那就告诉我一切
then you can tell me, everything.
桑杰 请替客人倒杯酒
Sanjay, make a drink for our guest, please.
干杯 我是普莉亚
Cheers. - Priya. - Hmm.
你才是幕后老大
This is your operation?
拿男人当傀儡在男人世界很有用
A masculine front in a man's world has its uses.
你找的军火商是安德烈萨托
The dealer you're looking for is Andrei Sator.
俄国的大财阀
The Russian oligarch.
-你认识他  -没有私交
- You know him? - Not personally.
靠天然气成为亿万富豪
Made his billions in gas.
听说在莫斯科失宠后搬到伦敦
Moved to London. Said to be on the outs with Moscow.
很好
Very good.
但他不是靠天然气致富 而是靠钚元素
Except the gas he made his billions from was actually plutonium.
这不能解释你为何或如何 把逆转子弹卖给他
None of which explains how or why you sold him inverted munitions.
我卖子弹给他的时候 它们都很普通
When I sold him the rounds, they were perfectly ordinary.
他是怎么逆转子弹
So how did he get them inverted?
我们认为他只是个掮客
We believe he's functioning as some sort of a broker.
现在和未来的中间人
Between our time and the future.
他能和未来的人沟通
He can communicate with the future?
我们都行啊 电邮 信用卡 简讯
We all do, don't we? E-mails, credit cards, texts.
任何纪录都能直接和未来的人沟通
Anything that goes into the record speaks directly to the future.
问题是 未来的人能回应吗
The question is, can the future speak back?
我要负责查出来
And I'm supposed to find out?
想靠近萨托就需要全新的主人翁
To get anywhere near Sator would take a fresh-faced protagonist.
你就是最好的人选
And you are fresh as a daisy.
接近他 查出他用什么方法收到什么
Get close. Find out what he's receiving and how.
让英国情报局介入安全吗
Is it safe to involve British Intelligence?
我有个萨托动不了的联络人
I have a contact who's out of Sator's reach.
你一定有逃走的计划
You must've had a plan for getting out.
我并不喜欢
Not one I love.
我能效劳吗
May I help you, sir?
我是寇斯比先生的午餐
I'm Mr. Crosby's lunch.
我假设你和麦可寇斯比爵士约吃午餐
I presume you mean Sir Michael Crosby's lunch.
尽管假设吧
Presume away.
请跟我来
If you'll follow me.
我先吃了 别介意
Started without you. Hope you don't mind.
我会跟上的
I'll catch up.
我要一样的
Same for me, please.
我叫服务生来
I'll send the waiter.
交代一声就行了
No, just pass on the order.
我猜你对某个俄国人士有兴趣
I gather you have an interest in a certain Russian national.
英俄人士 我得格外小心
Anglo-Russian. So I have to watch my step.
没错 他是英国情报局的线人
Indeed. He's tapped into the intelligence services.
我警告过他们 他都乱给情报
I've warned them he's feeding them rubbish...
但他们似乎不在乎
but they don't seem to care.
跟我说说他
Tell me about him.
你应该对 苏联时期的秘密城市很熟悉
I assume you're familiar with the Soviet-era secret cities.
地图上找不到的封闭城市 建立在敏感企业周围
Closed cities, not shown on maps. Built around sensitive industries.
多数都已开放 也重新命名为一般城镇
Most of them have been opened up and renamed as regular towns.
但萨托成长的城市并不是 史托斯克12市
Not the one Sator grew up in.
出了意外 后来就用来做地下核试验
Some kind of accident. After which it was used for underground tests.
两星期前 发生基辅歌剧院突袭的同一天
Two weeks ago, same day as the Kiev opera siege,
我们发现北西伯利亚发生核爆
we spotted a detonation in northern Siberia,
就在史托斯克12市的旧址
just where Stalsk-12 was.
萨托从地图上的空白中崛起
Sator emerged from this blank spot on the map
野心勃勃 砸下大钱进入英国体制
with ambition... and enough money to buy his way into the British establishment.
透过他妻子
Through his wife?
凯萨琳巴顿 佛德瑞克巴顿爵士的大侄女
Katherine Barton. Oldest niece of Sir Frederick Barton.
她在薛普利拍卖行工作 拍卖会上认识了萨托
She works at Shipley's. Met Sator at an auction.
婚姻幸福
A happy marriage?
早已形同陌路
Practically estranged.
-我要怎么接近萨托  -当然是透过她
Well, how do I get to Sator?
非也
Hardly.
我们有一张王牌
We have an ace in the hole.
你用购物袋装哥雅名画
You're carrying a Goya in a Harrods bag.
这是西班牙人阿雷波画的假画
It's a fake by a Spaniard named Arepo.
从瑞士伯恩没收来的其中一幅
One of two we've confiscated from an embezzler in Bern.
另一幅怎么了
What happened to the other one?
经过凯萨琳监定后 出现在薛普利拍卖行
It turned up at Shipley's. Authenticated by Katherine Barton.
然后拿去拍卖 你猜被谁买走
Put on auction. And who do you think bought it?
她丈夫
Her husband?
Mmm-hmm.
她知道是假画吗
Does she know it's a forgery?
很难说
Oh, it's hard to say.
谣传她和阿雷波关系亲密
Rumor has it that she and Arepo were close.
嗯
Uh-huh.
别介意喔
Look, no offense,
但你若想假冒一个亿万富豪
but in this world, when someone is claiming to be a billionaire...
穿平价西装可骗不了人
Brooks Brothers won't cut it.
我的预算有限
I'm assuming I'm on a budget.
先拯救世界再核销开支
Save the world, then we'll balance the books.
让我推荐一位裁缝师
Can I recommend a tailor?
不用劳您大驾
I'll manage.
不是你们英国人才会狗眼看人低
You British don't have a monopoly on snobbery, you know.
你误会了 我们只想插一脚
Well, not a monopoly. More of a controlling interest.
麻烦帮我打包
Could you box that up for me?
想都别想
Certainly not.
再见 麦可爵士
Goodbye, Sir Michael.
坎农街3号
薛普利拍卖行
我能效劳吗
How can I help, sir?
抱歉 您没预约 这位先生
Sorry, I wasn't notified of any appointments, Mr...
哥雅
Goya.
哥雅先生
Mr. Goya.
不是 我听说你能监定哥雅名画
No. I'm told you're the person to see about Goya.
太了不起了
That's extraordinary.
值多少钱
What's it worth?
先别急
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
估价前要做很多监定
Lots of work to do before any kind of valuation.
收藏历史 显微镜和X光检验
Provenance, microscopic examination, X-rays.
你的直觉是什么
But what does your heart tell you?
你说是向谁买下这幅画
Sir, where did you say you acquired this drawing?
汤玛士阿雷波
Tomas Arepo.
我用几分美金 向愤怒的瑞士银行家买下这幅画
I bought my Goya for cents on a dollar from an irate Swiss banker.
追溯到阿雷波 才发现我挖到宝
Traced it back to Arepo, then realized I scored a bargain
因为他告诉我 谁用高价买下他另一幅假画
when he told me who paid top dollar for another one of his pictures.
-你先生 -你挖到什么宝
- Your husband. - Where's your bargain?
这画显然是假的
Your drawing's an obvious fake.
我的画是幅逼真的假画 你比谁都清楚
My drawing's a very good fake.
我帮忙诈骗自己老公这件事
The information that I helped defraud my own husband?
他和我算是同行 但想见到他真的很难
He and I are in related businesses, but he's a very hard man to meet.
-假如我们谈笔交易 -交易
If you and I were to make an arrangement...
别这么怕这字眼 我先生并不怕
Don't be afraid of the word. My husband isn't.
很遗憾 他抢先你一步
I'm sorry to tell you he got there first.
他早就知道却没有采取行动
He knows? And he's never done anything about it?
-何必呢  -他被骗了9百万美元啊
Why would he? He paid $9 million for it.
不过就是他逼我们度假的花费
Barely cover the cost of the holiday he just forced us on.
去火星度假吗
Where'd you go, Mars?
越南 坐我们的游艇 他的游艇
Vietnam, on our yacht. His yacht.
你一身高级西装 名鞋 名表
You've got the suit. The shoes, the watch.
却有点自不量力
Think you're a little out of your depth.
像你先生这种财富庞大的有钱人
People who've amassed fortunes, like your husband's,
通常不会容忍自己被诈骗
generally aren't okay with being cheated out of any of it.
那幅画是用来控制我的把柄
The drawing is his hold over me.
他威胁要报警 让我坐牢
He threatened me with police. Prison. The works.
他控制我
He controls me.
我和儿子的相处 所有的一切
My contact with my son. Everything.
离开他本就很难 现在更不可能了
Leaving would never have been easy but now it's impossible.
我反抗不了他
You can't fight.
只能哀求他
Just beg.
我在越南试过再去爱他
In Vietnam, I tried to love him again.
以为如果有爱 他就会把儿子还给我
Thought if there was love there, he might give me my son back.
我们坐在天杀的游艇上看夕阳
We sat on that bloody boat watching the sunsets,
重温昔日幸福时光
imitating some earlier time in our lives.
他似乎很快乐 于是我问他
He seemed happy, so I asked him.
他提出条件
And he made me an offer.
我不再见儿子他就放我走
He'd let me go if I agreed never to see my son again.
我表达了意见 把麦斯带上岸
I expressed myself. I took Max ashore.
他带着悔意打给我 当我们回到游艇
He called us, contrite.
我却看到一个女人跳下海 然后他就消失不见
And when we got back, I glimpsed some other woman diving off the boat, and he'd vanished.
我从来没这么嫉妒过
I never felt such envy.
你不像是会嫉妒的人
You don't seem the jealous type.
我嫉妒她的自由
Of her freedom.
你知道我有多想跳下海吗
You know how I dream of just diving off that boat?
但你们有个儿子
But you share a son.
那就是我现在的生活
That's my life now.
你当时知道那是幅假画吗
Did you know the drawing was a fake?
不知道 我和汤玛士变得很亲密 也许太亲密了
No. Tomas and I became close, maybe too close.
我让他失望了
I failed.
安德烈不懂失望的感觉 只觉得遭到背叛
Andrei can't conceive of failure, only betrayal.
但我没有背叛我丈夫
But I didn't betray my husband.
回头看 或许我错失机会
Retrospect, maybe I missed my chance.
而他则放阿雷波走
And he let Arepo walk free.
如果你真的见过阿雷波
If you'd actually met Arepo as you claimed,
就会知道他早已不能走路
you'd understand he no longer walks anywhere.
-我们只讲过电话 -他也不能讲电话
We spoke on the phone. He can't do that either.
-那幅画呢  -要干嘛
- Where's the drawing? - Why?
把我介绍给他 我就把画偷走
Get me an introduction. I'll take the drawing out of the equation.
没有画就不能告你 也不能威胁你
No picture, no prosecution, no more hold over you.
我是你的第二次机会
I might just be your second chance.
不 我不需要救赎
No, I don't need redemption.
你要背叛他
At betrayal.
你先生的朋友
Friends of your husband's?
你早就知道了
You knew this was going to happen?
放心 他们不会杀你
Don't worry, they won't kill you.
安德烈不喜欢和当地警察打交道
Andrei dislikes tangling with local law enforcement on that level.
你一定很不喜欢我的长相
You must've really not liked the look of me.
你的长相没问题
The look of you's fine.
最好先来狠的 免得我三心两意
It's best to get to the nasty part before I care one way or the other.
你左边口袋有个号码 别从家里打来
There's a number in your left coat pocket. Don't call from home.
你不会接到我的电话
You won't be taking my call.
别小看我
I might surprise you.
我一小时前就点了辣椒酱
I ordered my hot sauce an hour ago.
能不能快点走
Can we get going?
拜托
Please?
他要你亲眼看见
He wants you to see.
然后再得到他要的
And he gets what he wants.
他也有吃鳖的一天
Not always, apparently.
安娜说我们要去庞贝看火山熔岩
Anna says we're going to Pompeii
我也会去
I'll be there, too!
我就说别小看我
Told you I'd surprise you.
-他很可爱 -他是我的一切
He's a cute kid. He's everything.
那幅画在哪
Where's the drawing?
奥斯陆的机场
Oslo. At the airport.
机场
The airport?
知道自由港是什么吗
Do you know what a Freeport is?
-专门储放艺术品的港口仓库 -尚未课税的艺术品
A storage facility for art that was acquired... But not yet taxed.
我们建立了一个网络
We started a network.
路特速营造公司负责盖仓库 我负责引进客户
Rotas, this construction company, built them. I brought in the clients.
这些仓库是避税天堂
The facilities are tax havens.
自由港
客户可以看到他们的投资 却不必进口到国内
The clients can view their investments without importing them,
这样就不必缴税
so they avoid paying tax.
就像是艺术品的转机贵宾室
It's sorta like a transit lounge for art?
艺术品 古董
Art, antiquities.
-任何贵重物品 -任何东西
- Anything of value, really. - Anything?
任何合法的东西
Anything legal.
就像是瑞士银行系统 完全隐密
But it's not unlike the Swiss banking system. Opaque.
你应该知道自由港多半只有仓库
As I'm sure you are aware, most Freeports are just warehouses.
但我们能确保你能享受
But here we ensure that you can actually enjoy...
路特速在奥斯陆自由港有仓库 我猜画在那里
Rotas has assets in the Oslo Freeport. I'm guessing it's there.
保险库在这里
And this way to the vaults!
-你猜  -她猜的
- Guessing? - Guessing?
我们每年去那里四五次
We make trips there four, five times a year.
-去看艺术品  -还有去干他的勾当
- To view art? - And whatever it is he does.
但艺术品对安德烈来说并不重要
Turns out art's of no importance to Andrei.
自由港才重要
But the Freeports are.
保险库是根据五角大厦结构建造
The structure of the vaults is based on the Pentagon.
每个保险库都有独立的结构体
Each vault a separate structure within the others.
破坏一个结构体不会影响其它的
Damage to one structure won't compromise the others.
火警
设有生物识别器 直接从
Some of our clients opt for biometric access, straight in...
机场跑道进出
off the tarmac.
从机场航厦
From the terminal?
从他们的私人飞机
From their private planes.
当然了
Of course.
我们的后勤部门 从世界其它自由港运送货物
Our logistics department ships to and from
你想在那里找到什么
What are you hoping to find in there?
你真想知道
You really wanna know?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
带一些防辐射手套
Bring some lead-lined gloves.
天啊 是核武
Jesus.
注意防火措施
pay attention to the fire precautions.
-文件特别怕 -火灾 当然了
Documents are vulnerable to...
我们不用洒水系统
We don't use sprinklers.
仓库会灌满卤烷
The facility is flooded with halide gas,
几秒内就能排除空气
displacing all the air within seconds.
你能示范吗
Can you show me?
我们会窒息而死
If I did, we'd suffocate.
员工呢
What about the staff?
卤烷只会灌满保险库 他们得逃进两边的走廊
Halide only fills the vaults, they just have to get into either corridor,
而且会有10秒的警告
and there is a 10-second warning.
至少你给他们10秒逃命
At least you give them 10 seconds.
客户会用我们就是因为 他们的货比我们的命更值钱
Well, sir, our clients use us because we have no priorities above their property.
真要命
Blimey.
全都是防火门
All doors are fireproof.
液压开关 简单的钥匙和电子触发器
Hydraulic closers, simple key and electronic triggers.
全面封锁后要开启其实很容易
Surprisingly easy once there's a lockdown.
为何会全面封锁
Why a lockdown?
电源安全开关会导致外门密封
Power switches to fail-safes, sealing the outer doors,
但内门就回到原厂设定
but inner doors revert to factory settings.
锁头很容易撬开 简直就是小儿科
And pickable locks.
该怎么挟带重装武器 而不会触发封锁程序
So, how do we get enough firepower through the perimeter to trigger the lockdown procedure?
自由港的后墙
Back wall of the Freeport.
你有点子
You've got something?
你不会喜欢
Not gonna like it.
你想撞毁一架飞机
You wanna crash a plane?
又不是让它坠毁 没那么夸张
Well, not from the air. Don't be so dramatic.
我要让一架喷射客机偏离跑道 撞上后墙引发一场大火
I want to run a jet off the taxiway and breach the rear wall and start a fire.
多大的飞机
Well, how big a plane?
那部分就有点夸张了
Well, that part is a little dramatic.
这是米耶 他的小组会搞定飞机
This is Mahir.
挪威货运航空公司
Norsk Freight.
他们使用自由港西侧的机库
They use the hangar on the west side of the Freeport.
你要撞毁货机 机组员怎么办
You want to crash a transport plane? What about the crew?
解开逃生滑梯 让他们逃命
We pop the slides, chuck 'em off.
在飞机滑行中
On the move?
有什么问题 他们不会有事
What's the problem? They'll be fine.
这太胆大妄为了
Well, it seems bold.
胆大妄为不错啊 我以为你会说疯狂
Bold I'm fine with. I thought you were gonna say nuts.
被抓了怎么办
And if you get caught?
不会啦
We won't.
万一呢
And if you do?
大家会以为是恐攻 但没人死亡
Everyone assumes terrorism, but no one's died,
快速引渡后逃过牢狱之灾 根本就不会上新闻
so swift extradition then lost in the system. It'll barely make the news.
这要看爆炸有多大
Oh, depends on the size of your explosion.
其实金条一定会引起大骚动
Well, actually, the gold bars might get some play.
金条
Gold bars?
挪威货运每月运送金条到国库
Norsk Freight ships Treasury gold once a month.
炸掉后货舱 金条散落在跑道
Blow the back. Drop it out on the runway.
我保证没人会注意仓库
No one will be looking at the building. I guarantee you.
五角仓库的中央空间太大了
The space in the center of the pentagon is too big.
那里有什么东西
There's something there.
但查不出来 平面图上没记号
Can't figure it out, it's just not marked.
45秒
That's 45 seconds.
绰绰有余
Ample.
你不是还得狂奔吗
Won't you be running?
好吧 换你了 开始打包
All right, it's your turn. Start packing.
各位 请通过安检门
Gentlemen, if you would, through the detector, please.
先生
Sir?
请问要喝咖啡或水
I can offer you, perhaps, a coffee, water?
给我杯浓缩咖啡
No, I'll take an espresso.
-您呢  -不用 谢谢
- Sir? - No, thank you.
太好了
Excellent.
大家都吃素吗 我只有素食餐
Is everybody on this plane vegetarian? Because all I got here is vegetarian.
那看起来像是肉
So that looks like meat,
不过应该是素的 看起来都是素的
but I think that looks vegetarian. I think they both look vegetarian.
我也不知道 我被搞混了
I don't really know. It's confusing, ya know?
好吧
Okay.
这里请 两位
This way, gentlemen.
两位 你们的储藏室
Gentlemen, your assigned compartment.
继续开 别用无线电
Carry on. Not the radio.
挪威货运
瑜珈
Yoga.
快走 快啊
Let's go! Now!
快点 快点
Go, go, go!
好吧
Right. Um...
你说10秒 对吧
You said 10 seconds, right?
这里有别人
There's someone in here with us.
路特速
-要帮忙吗  -好啊
- Need a hand? - Actually, yes.
别碰
Don't touch them!
到底发生什么事
The hell happened here?
事情还没发生
It hasn't happened yet.
别杀他
Don't kill him!
我们得知道身分是否曝光
We need to know if we've been compromised.
你为何在这里 你是谁
Why are you here? Who are you?
你怎么知道我们在这
How'd you know we'd be here?
我们得走了
We need to go.
另一个家伙怎么了
What happened to the other guy?
搞定了
Took care of him.
我看太多了
Well, I've seen too much.
我还活着 这代表你决定信任我
I'm still alive, which must mean you've decided to trust me.
也许我不够狠
Or maybe I lost my edge.
你还是够狠
Edge is still intact.
发生一场冷战
There's a cold war.
核战
Nuclear?
时间战争
Temporal.
时空旅行
Time travel?
不
No.
能够逆转物质中熵的科技
Technology that can invert an object's entropy.
你是指逆转时间
You mean reverse chronology.
就像费曼与惠勒的理论 正子只是时间逆行的电子
Like Feynman and Wheeler's notion that a positron is an electron
-我是物理硕士 -那就试着跟上罗
I have a master's in physics.
必须完全保密
Beyond secret.
那为何找我来
Then why'd you bring me in?
我以为只会找到一幅画和几盒子弹
I thought we'd find a drawing and a couple boxes of bullets.
我比你更惊讶
Not as surprised as I was.
我要回孟买问个明白
I'm going back to Mumbai to get some answers.
我会让你当中间人 但是记住 对你来说
I'll set you up as a go-between. But remember, to you...
任务是找到钚元素
it's all about plutonium.
任务完成后 他们会杀你灭口
And when we're done, they'll kill you.
你不是会杀我灭口吗
Won't you have to do that anyway?
我宁愿自己做决定
I'd rather it be my decision.
我也是
So would I.
希望啦
I think.
你干的
Your work?
运送金条货机撞毁
你在保险库找到什么
What did you find in the vaults?
两个敌人 其中一个逆行
Two antagonists. One inverted.
我们除掉那个正常的 但逆行的逃走了
We took out the regular one, but the inverted one got away.
两人同时出现
Both emerged at the same moment?
对
Yeah.
他们是同一个人
They were the same person.
萨托在保险库装了一道逆转门
Sator's built a turnstile in that vault.
逆转门
Turnstile?
逆转时间的机器
A machine for inverting.
你告诉我那项科技还没有被发明
You've told me that technology hasn't been invented yet.
是没有 是未来的人给他的
It hasn't.
你有机会查个明白
You have the best chance of finding out.
-见到他了吗  -差一点
-Have you met him?  -I was close.
-他需要什么…如果你需要  -比如说
-What if you have… something he needs?  - Such as?
钚-241
Plutonium-241.
萨托试图从中情局小队那里 抢走唯一没登记的钚241
Sator tried to lift the only loose 241 from under a CIA team
就是那次基辅歌剧院突击行动
at the opera siege in Kiev.
他杀了小队 但没拿到钚241
He got the team.
乌克兰国家安全局
Ukrainian Security Services.
一周内会运到塔林
It's moving to Tallinn in a week.
帮助军火商窃取武器级钚元素 是绝不能容许的 普莉亚
Helping an arms dealer steal weapons-grade plutonium is unacceptable, Priya.
我只要把他干掉就行
I'm just gonna take him out.
不行 萨托必须活着
No, no, no. Sator has to stay alive.
直到我们知道他到底扮演什么角色
He has to stay alive until we know his part in things.
趁机查明真相 但不能失去钚241
Leverage the situation, without losing control of the 241.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
恐怖份子的核弹 就算能杀死数十亿人口
A terrorist's bomb, even one that can kill billions,
但若不能阻止萨托 后果远比那更严重
is nothing compared with what will happen if we don't stop Sator.
阻止他做什么
From doing what?
我们遭到来自未来的攻击
We are being attacked by the future.
萨托在帮助他们 你得查出他的方法
And Sator's helping. You have to find out how.
我看到奥斯陆的新闻 拿到画了吗
I saw the news from Oslo. Do you have the drawing?
你不必再担心了
You don't have to worry about it anymore.
你毁了那幅画
You destroyed it?
我觉得你不会想要拿回来
I didn't think you'd want it back.
他知道吗
Does he know?
还不知道 你先耐心等待
Not yet. So sit tight.
耐心等待
Sit tight?
我儿子和那禽兽相处愈久 就会愈来愈疏远我
Every day my son spends with that monster, he thinks a little less of me.
你不会等太久的 尽快把我介绍给他
It won't be long. In the meantime, introduce me.
以什么身分
As what?
前任美国驻利雅德大使馆一等秘书
I'm a former first secretary from the American Embassy in Riyadh.
我们去年6月在宴会上认识
We met at a party last June.
我们在利雅德参加过宴会 但不是在6月
We were at a party in Riyadh, but I don't think it was in June.
6月29日 7点或7点半
It was June 29th. 7:00 or 7:30.
菜单上是鲑鱼 那晚改成鲈鱼
Salmon was on the printed menu. Swapped for sea bass on the night.
萨托提早离开 他走后我们才认识
Sator left early. That's when we met.
后来我去伦敦的薛普利拍卖行 你在这里遇见我
I came into Shipley's in London. You ran into me here
想带我看你的游艇
and wanna show me your yacht.
他会以为我们搞外遇
He'll think we're having an affair.
那他会更想见我
Then he'll wanna meet me.
或是杀了你
Or have you killed.
这一点不用你担心
Let me worry about that.
我看起来担心吗
Did I look worried?
除了船员能睡70人 包括两架直升机 防御飞弹
Sleeps 70 with crew.
怕海盗吗
Two helicopters. Missile defenses. Afraid of pirates?
安德烈和黑白两道打交道 得罪两边 这就是避难所
Andrei lives playing one government off the other.
我能跟你上船吗
The day they turn, that's his refuge. May I join you?
瓦克夫不见得会允许
Not sure Volkov's taking passengers just now.
那就搭我的船
Then we'll take mine.
麦斯
Max!
那个美国人是谁
Who's the American?
是个朋友
He's a friend.
他去过拍卖行
The man from Shipley's.
你想找人痛扁他
Who you tried to have beaten up.
我再问一次 他是谁
I ask again, who is he?
我们去年6月 在利雅德美国大使馆认识
We met in Riyadh last June at the American Embassy.
这个外交官的身手不错嘛
Good with fists for a diplomat.
你的疑心病太重了 安德烈
Paranoia's your department, Andrei.
他人很好 我邀他来共进晚餐
He seems nice. I invited him to the dinner.
麦斯
Max?
他去了庞贝和赫库兰尼姆
He's visiting Pompeii and Herculaneum.
你就把他送走 我答应陪他去的
You just sent him off? I promised him I'd go with him.
我跟他说你在忙
I explained you were busy.
忙着陪朋友
With your friend.
别乱摸 要摸也得先请我吃晚饭
Hey, easy, fella. Where I'm from, you buy me dinner first.
-萨托先生 -省省吧
- Mr. Sator. - Don't bother.
告诉我你上了我老婆没有
Just tell me if you've slept with my wife yet.
没有
Uh... No.
还没有
Not yet.
你想怎么死
How would you like to die?
老死
Old.
你挑错行业了
You chose the wrong profession.
前面有一座有围墙的花园 我们要带你去 割断你咽喉
There's a walled garden up the road. We are going to take you there, cut your throat.
不是横割 是在中间割出一个洞
Not across. In the middle, like a hole.
然后割下你的蛋 塞进洞里面 塞爆气管
Then we take your balls and we stuff them in the cut,block the windpipe.
太复杂了
Complex.
看着你讨厌的人在窒息而死之前
It's very gratifying to watch a man you don't like
想把自己的蛋挖出来 感觉很爽
try to pull his own balls out of his throat before he chokes.
这是你的待客之道
Is this how you treat all your guests?
话讲完了
We're finished.
爱看歌剧吗
Do you like opera?
又怎样
Well?
这里不好讲话
Not here.
会驾帆船吗
You sail?
我随便玩过
I've messed around on boats.
8点整来港口 这次不只是玩玩
Be on the dock at 8:00 ready to do more than mess around.
早上8点
麦斯今年缺课太多次了
Max has missed too much school this year.
我要带他回英国 学校不会容许他缺课这么多
I'm taking him back to England.
你虽然富可敌国
You have all the trappings of a king.
但只是在玩权力游戏的奸诈小人
We both know you're a grubby little man playing power games
有个不再爱你的老婆
with a wife who doesn't love you anymore.
你今天
You seem...
很会呛声嘛
spirited today.
-是吗  -是真的
- Do I? - Yes, you do.
你担心那幅画被毁了
Were you worried it had been destroyed?
放心 我的直觉告诉我 把它从保险库拿出来
Rest assured, instinct told me to remove it from the vault.
我对未来总是有敏锐的直觉
I've always had instincts about the future.
我就是靠它建立这个 你不再珍惜的生活
That's how I built this life you no longer value.
去驾船还是潜水
Sailing or diving?
升起
Rising!
你对歌剧知道多少
What do you know about opera?
2008年 一座偏远的俄罗斯导弹基地
In 2008, a remote Russian missile station
遭到攻击并被占领一星期
was overwhelmed and held for a week.
那座基地被夺回来
When the station was retaken,
但核弹弹头的钚241 却少了3/4公斤
丢失的钚241
The missing 241
于14号在基辅歌剧院突袭时出现
surfaced at the opera house siege in Kiev on the 14th.
转向
Coming about!
你有何提议
What do you propose?
合伙
Partnership.
我不会跟你合伙
I wouldn't partner with you.
你懂得怎么自保 没留下任何纪录
You can take care of yourself. You have no record.
受过训练的军火商 知道怎么掩盖自己的痕迹
Someone in the arms trade, with training, who knows how to cover his tracks.
这是众所周知的事
Not that shocking.
一个情报员当然知道
For an intelligence agent.
右转
Right!
下地狱吧 安德烈
Burn in hell, Andrei.
你不能这样驾船
You can't jibe a boat like this!
有必要就行
You can if you have to.
-凯特 -让他溺死就算了
- Kat... - Why didn't you let him drown?
我需要他
I need him.
卖枪给他
What, to sell guns?
我不是你想的那种人
I'm not who you think I am.
我知道 他给我看了那幅画
Well, that I know. He showed me the drawing.
抱歉 我得接近他
I'm sorry. I had to get close to him.
我不知道你以为你先生在做什么
I don't know what you think your husband does...
大家都知道他是军火商
Oh, we both know he's an arms dealer.
不只是这样
He's so much more.
那是怎样
What, then?
安德烈萨托掌控全人类的性命 不只是你的
Andrei Sator holds all of our lives in his hands, not just yours.
萨托先生要见你
Mr. Sator wants to see you.
好
Okay.
现在
Now.
他要看到我没穿裤子
Uh, he wants to see me without pants?
相信我
- Trust me. - Save it.
省省吧 我不会再上第二次当
I'm not falling for it twice.
你有更好的选择
You have a better option?
你会不择手段得到你要的
Whatever it takes to get what you want.
根本不会管我跟儿子的死活
Not a second's thought for me or my son.
你觉得他会怎么对付我
What do you think he's gonna do to me now?
尽量别用它
Try not to use it.
别对任何人开枪
On anyone.
够了
Enough.
瞧 我和年轻小伙子一样健康
See? Pulse of a man half my age.
陪我喝酒
Drink with me.
看来我欠你一条命
It seems I now owe you my life.
小事一件
It's nothing.
我的命可不是小事
My life is not nothing.
我也不喜欢亏欠别人
And I don't like to be in debt.
那就回报我 别报复你老婆
Then pay me. No retribution against your wife.
你以为是她松开我的安全索
You think she released my harness?
那是我自己的错
It was my own mistake.
那就帮我偷走钚241
Then help me steal the 241.
我需要资源 那是武器化的钚元素
I need resources. It's weapons-grade plutonium.
必须小心处理 也需要封隔设施
That means special handling, containment facilities...
我很清楚
I know what it means.
你要教我幅射的危险
You lecture me about radiation?
安德烈萨托
Andrei Sator,
从年少就在废墟中挖掘钚元素
digging plutonium from the rubble of my city as a teenager.
在哪里
Where?
史托斯克12市
Stalsk-12.
我的家乡
My home.
一枚核弹在地面引爆 碎片四处散落
One part of a warhead exploded at ground level, scattering the others.
政府需要有人找到钚元素
They needed people to find the plutonium.
那是我第一笔生意 没人敢竞标
It became my first contract.
他们都觉得必死无疑
Nobody else even bid. They thought it was a death sentence.
但是
But...
一个人死亡的可能
one man's probability of death...
安德烈萨托
却是另一个人存活的可能
...is another man's possibility for a life.
我在全新俄罗斯占有一席之地
I staked my claim in the new Russia.
直到现在 只有我的公司能在废墟中作业
Even now, my company is the only one to operate in the ruins.
钚241经由欧洲北部被运送到
The 241 is being transported through northern Europe,
位于第里雅斯特的长期核武库
on its way to the long-term nuclear storage depot in Trieste.
听说你在塔林有人脉
I'm told you have resources in Tallinn.
留下来过夜
Stay with us tonight.
我坚持
I insist.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
好好谈谈今天的事
We're going to talk about today.
才不要
No, we're not.
不要
No?
走着瞧
We'll see.
别以为你能像 对付别的女人一样对付我
Don't think for a second you can treat me like you treat your other women.
那么
And, uh...
你以为 我是怎么对付别的女人
how do you imagine...I treat these other women, huh?
我会逼她们乖乖说话
You think I force them into conversation?
你不想说没关系 用力咬着吧
You wanna be quiet, fine.You can bite down on that.
就连你空洞的灵魂也需要填补
Even a soul as blank and brittle as yours needs a response.
光是恐惧和痛苦够吗
Is fear and pain enough, Andrei?
我只能给你这些
That's all I have to offer you.
那就够了
Well, that will have to do, then.
你为什么不放过我
Why didn't you just let me go?
因为
Because...
如果我不能拥有你
if I can't have you...
别人也休想拥有你
no one else can.
你敢碰我 我会叫到他听见
And if you touch me, I scream so loud he hears.
我会让他插手吗
You think I let him interfere?
他敢的话 你就得杀了他
If he tried, you'd have to kill him.
生意一笔勾销
End of deal.
所以你最好别碰我
So you leave me alone.
别来烦我
Not now!
98下 扁人后脉博还这么稳真不赖
Ninety-eight. Not bad for such exertion.
他在窗口偷看
He was at the window.
我只是好奇
I was curious.
你不该对我的货好奇
My property shouldn't concern you.
你是什么人
Who are you?
怎会知道歌剧院的事
How do you come by your information about the opera?
你不会跟个不够聪明的 中情局干员做生意吧
You wouldn't do business with someone who wasn't savvy enough to be recruited.
中情局提供市场上2/3的核原料
Hell, the CIA provides two thirds of the market for fissile material.
他们通常是买家 不是卖家
They're usually buying, not selling.
但我们活在一个暮光世界
But we do live in a twilight world.
惠特曼的诗句 很优美
Is that Whitman? Pretty.
下一个警告就是脑袋吃子弹
Next warning's a bullet in the brain.
不是咽喉里塞卵蛋
No balls in my throat?
到了塔林就没有时间搞这种事
There will be no time for such things... in Tallinn.
你设法去那里 我要瓦克夫加入你小组
You make your way there. I want Volkov on your team.
办不到
No.
我负责偷货 你负责给钱
I spring the material. You pay me off.
你太太负责交易
Your wife does the exchange.
我从不让她涉入我的生意
I never involve her in my business.
所以我才信任她
Yeah, that's why I trust her.
送他上岸
Put him ashore.
我要怎么联络你
How do I contact you?
你不能
You don't.
你要怎么付我头期款
How do you advance me the funds?
你最好别把钚元素掉地上
Handle the plutonium better than that.
金条上面发现什么
What did you find on the gold?
没印记 没模具痕迹 啥都没有
No franks, no mold marks. Nothing.
-哪儿来的  -情报点
- How? - Dead drops.
他埋下时空胶囊 传送位置
He buries his time capsule, transmits the location,
然后挖出未来送来的逆转物品
then digs it up to collect the inverted materials they sent.
一瞬间就送到 他埋在哪里
Seemingly instantaneous. Where's he bury it?
几世纪都不会被发现的地方
Some place that won't be discovered for centuries.
土壤分析显示什么
What did the soil samples show?
欧洲北部 亚洲 有放射性
Northern Europe, Asia.
为何找我来
Why am I here?
我不信任别人进行监定
I don't trust anyone else to assess the pieces.
车队会经过市区 你觉得怎样
Via convoy through downtown, what's the thinking?
马路太拥挤 车况很难预料
Crowded. Unpredictable traffic patterns.
几乎不可能策划突袭行动
It's almost impossible to plan an ambush.
说得有道理
They have a point.
他们从空中监视车队
Is the convoy monitored from the air?
GPS定位 转错一个弯 大队人马就会赶来
Tracked by GPS. One wrong turn, in come the cavalry.
我们需要重装武器
We need big guns.
可以展示武力 也不必开火
Guns that make the point without being fired.
我们需要一辆看起来不快的快车
We need a fast car that doesn't look fast.
四辆重型车
Four heavy vehicles.
公共汽车  长途汽车  18轮车
A bus, coach,18 wheeler.
其中一个必须是消防车
One of them has to be a fire truck.
最重要的是绝对不能留下任何纪录
Most of all, we have to set this up with nothing in the record.
电子和纸本都不行
Nothing electronic, nothing paper.
把货偷走后不能让萨托突袭我们
I don't want Sator ambushing us once we spring the material.
他被蒙在鼓里我们才安全
His ignorance is our only protection.
自由港
看到吗 凯特
You see, Kat?
一些我的最爱
Some of my favorites.
被烧过但仍能用 对吧
Singed but, uh, salvageable, wouldn't you say?
那不是我的专长
- That's not my area of expertise.
没错 你跟这种事不会有关系
Ah, that's right.You would never have anything to do with such things.
但我们的世界在此碰撞
But this is where our worlds collide.
这是什么 安德烈
What is this, Andrei?
你心知肚明 凯特
You know perfectly well what it is, Kat.
这门肮脏龌龊的生意
The filthy business
让你穿得光鲜亮丽 也让我们儿子念名校
that put those clothes on your back and our boy in his school,
你还以为是你靠关系得来的
that you thought you could negotiate your way around.
车队10分钟后抵达市区
该走了
Time to go.
我才不会跟他走
I'm not going anywhere with him.
看着我
Look at me!
搞清楚一件事 你不能与虎谋皮
And understand, you don't negotiate with a tiger.
只能欣赏他 直到他反扑
You admire a tiger until he turns on you
就会知道他有多威猛
and you feel its true fucking nature!
别过来
Don't.
给我待在那里
You stay right there.
绿组 两分钟
Green. Two minutes.
你不会杀我
You are not going to kill me.
我已经试过了
I already tried.
你只敢把我推下船 而没胆冷血拿枪杀我
You pushed me off a boat. You are not going to shoot me in cold blood.
我的血在沸腾 安德烈
My blood's not cold, Andrei.
对 但你不够愤怒
No, but you're not angry enough.
因为愤怒会变成绝望
Because anger scars over into despair.
我看着你的双眼
I look in your eyes...
只看到绝望
I see despair.
贱女人 只会靠我养
Vengeful bitch! Living off me!
我还以为你没这么贱 够了
Thinking that you're better! Enough!
告诉我发生的一切
Tell me everything as it happens.
把我锁在这一边
Seal me this side.
黄组 60秒
Yellow, 60 seconds.
60秒 收到
蓝组 45秒
Blue, 45 seconds.
蓝组 45秒 收到
Blue, 45, check.
红组正开向你
Okay, Red. Coming to you.
三台货车到位
观察一切 向我回报
Watch everything. Give me all the details.
大家准备好了吗
All right, everyone set?
上吧 黄组
Go, Yellow!
出了问题
We got a problem!
我们需要支援 靠
Backup, we need backup! Shit!
无线电失效
他们还在移动吗
仔细听无线电对话
Check the radio chatter.
我看过每种武器等级的容器 这不是其中之一
I've seen samples of encapsulation in every weapons class. This is not one of them.
那就是他要的
That's what he's after.
我听不懂
Can't understand this.
你说你懂爱沙尼亚语
You said you spoke Estonian.
这不是爱沙尼亚语 是倒着说的话
It's not Estonian. It's backwards.
那是怎么回事
The hell is that?
快 快
Go, go, go!
别交给他
Don't give it to him.
-这不是钚元素 -这更可怕 该死
This isn't plutonium. It's worse than that, God damn it!
抱歉
Sorry.
他逃走了
He's getting away.
他把她留在车上
He left her in the car!
快追上她 快啊
Go after her, go! Go, go, go!
开到旁边
Pull up alongside!
快啊 靠近一点
Come on, come on. Closer!
稳住 稳住
Keep it steady, keep it steady!
快点
Hurry up!
拜托
Please!
别着急 我要呼叫救兵
All right, sit tight. I'm calling the cavalry.
哪来的救兵
What cavalry?
你不说实话她就死
If you are not telling the truth, she dies.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
你放在车上 不是消防车上 对吧
You left it in the car, not the fire truck, right?
谁跟你说的
- Who told you that? - Just tell me now,
老实说 真的在BMW车上吗
is it really in the BMW?
不知道
I don't know.
你不说我就再开枪
Tell me or I'll shoot her again!
放了她
Leave her alone!
杀了他
Kill him!
我没空跟你耗
I don't have time to negotiate.
-听我说 -3
- Listen to me! - Three.
我能帮你
I can help you.
-救救我 -2
- Help me! - Two.
拜托
Please!
-不要 -1
- Don't! - One.
下一枪就脑袋开花
Next one's a bullet to the head.
-不 -1
- No! - One.
2、3
Two. Three.
好啦 好啦
Okay! Okay.
-我放在那辆BMW上 -我们要检查是不是真的
The car. The BMW. I left it in the BMW. We're going to check this is real.
在手套箱里
It's in the glove box!
你放在哪里
Where did you leave it?
轿车或消防车 哪一台
Car or fire truck, which one?
你放在哪一台车上  我去之前得知道
Which vehicle did you leave it in? I need to know before I go out there.
我告诉你了
I already told you.
我相信你
I believe you.
你要她 那就祝你们幸福
You wanted her here, I hope you'll be happy...
安全
Clear!
惠勒 检查另一边
Wheeler, go check the other side.
你们两个
You two.
他跑去哪了
Where did he go?
过去
The past.
在手套箱里
It's in the glove box!
我们要检查是不是真的
We're going to check this is real.
-3 2 1 -好啦
- Three, two, one. - Okay, okay...
下一枪就脑袋开花
Next one's a bullet to the head.
-不 -1
- No! No! - One.
-听我说 -2
- Listen to me. - Two.
我能帮你
I can help you.
我没空跟你耗
I don't have time to negotiate.
你不说我就再开枪
Tell me or I'll shoot her again.
-放了她 -老实说 真的在BMW车上吗
- Leave her alone! - Tell me now,
你放在车上 不是消防车上 对吧
You left it in the car, not the fire truck, right?
谁跟你说的
Who told you that?
你不说实话她就死
If you're not telling the truth, she dies.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
-医护人员 -到了
- Medic! - Check in.
她遭到枪伤
She's been shot?
把她带回这一边
Bring her back, this side.
她被逆转子弹射伤吗
Was she shot with an inverted round?
这是艾佛斯 他是自己人
This is Ives. He's one of us.
自己人 这些人是谁
"Us"! Who are these guys?
普莉亚的人 我们的人
Priya's. Ours.
萨托怎么会知道突袭行动
How did Sator know about the ambush?
有留下纪录
It's posterity.
光天化日下的突袭行动 不可能没有纪录
An ambush in the middle of the street can't stay out of the records.
屁啦 他知道我们的一举一动 每一个细节都知道
Bullshit! He knew every move we made! Every one of 'em.
有人告密 是谁 是你吗
Somebody talked. Who was it?
不是
- Was it you? - No. No.
你在每一个阶段都知道太多 我再问你一次
At every stage, you've known too much. I'm going to ask you again.
你有没有告密
Did you talk?
没人告密 他们展开时间钳形攻势
Nobody talked. They're running a temporal pincer movement.
什么
A what?
钳形攻势 不是空间 而是时间
The pincer movement. But not in space, in time.
他一半的组员顺着时间前进
Half his team moves forward through the event.
他先监控他们 最后再逆转时间展开攻击
He monitors them, and then attacks at the end moving backwards,
那时他已知道一切
knowing everything.
除了我把钚元素藏在哪里
Except for where I stashed the plutonium.
那并不是钚元素 对吧
Which isn't really plutonium, is it?
我说过那是他要的东西 你也告诉他东西在哪
I told you it was what he was after. And you just told him where it was.
我撒了谎
I lied.
天啊 你连这件事也撒谎
Jesus. You lied about it?
他没办法在房间内确认 反正他还是会射杀她
He couldn't verify inside the room. He'd have shot her anyway.
撒谎是标准行动程序
Lying is standard operating procedure.
伤口扩散得太大
It's spread too far.
什么意思
Meaning what?
她快死了
She's gonna die.
标准行动程序
Standard operating procedure.
救不了吗 我们不能做点什么
Can't you help her? Can we do something?
不能逆转病患然后稳定逆转辐射
Can't we stabilize the inverse radiation by inverting the patient?
要花好几天
Takes days.
走吧
Let's go.
我们几分钟前才掌控这台机器 之前是萨托的
We took control of this machine minutes ago. Before that, it's Sator's.
她在这一边能活多久
How long is she gonna live on this side?
最多3个钟头
Three hours, tops.
我要带她过去
I'm taking her through.
我不会让她死 我愿意冒险
I'm not gonna let her die. I'll take my chances.
没办法把你带回来
There's no way of bringing you back.
我们会找到另一台机器
We find another machine.
一星期前 在哪里
A week ago? Where?
奥斯陆
Oslo.
那在机场安检范围内的仓库 闯不进去的
That facility's inside an airport security perimeter. It's impregnable.
上个星期就可以
Mmm... It wasn't last week.
我们要闯进去 你还会帮我们吧
We're going in. You might as well help us.
这是反照窗 当你走向逆转门
This is a proving window. As you approach the turnstile,
要是在反照窗内看不到自己 就别进去机器里
if you don't see yourself in the proving window,
看不到逆行的自己走出逆转门 就代表你出不来
If you don't see yourself reverse-exit a machine,
你自己看
See for yourself.
这就是答案 走吧
There's your answer. Let's go.
她慢慢稳定下来 伤口缝合了 只需要时间康复
She's stabilizing slowly. I'll clean and close, but the rest is time.
需要多少时间
How long does she need?
4 5天 一星期最保险
Four, five days. A week to be sure.
尼尔 设法带我们去奥斯陆 我要再出去
Hey, Neil. Find a way to get us to Oslo. I'm going back out there.
去做什么
To do what?
阻止萨托拿着我给他的东西逃走
To stop Sator from getting away with whatever it is I just gave him.
你没给他 你骗他东西在哪里 等等
You didn't. You lied about where it was. Wait.
你是为了她回去
You're going out there for her.
他在过去威胁要杀她
He threatened to kill her in the past.
若真的下手 她现在会怎样
If he does, what happens to her here?
无从得知
That's unknowable.
你若想去改变过去 就不是在这里观察后果
If you're there to make a change, you're not here to observe its effect.
你相信什么
What do you believe?
发生过的已经发生了
What's happened's happened.
我们必须在此时此刻救她
We need to save her, here and now.
你若是再出去 就会双手奉上他要的东西
If you go back out there, you might hand him exactly what he's after.
别让他们把她带回去 好吗
Don't let them take her back through there.
时间不多了
We don't have a lot of time.
你何不替我们找个刚从奥斯陆运来 舒舒服服的货柜
So why don't you find us a nice, cozy shipping container that's just come off a ship from Oslo?
这么做太莽撞了
This is cowboy shit.
你一旦走出那道门 就不知道会惹上什么麻烦
You have no idea what you're getting yourself into
惠勒 告诉他
Wheeler, brief him.
你会需要自己的氧气瓶
You'll need your own air.
这里的氧气无法进入逆转的肺膜
Regular air won't pass through the membranes of inverted lungs.
第一条规则 别接触顺时间前进的自己
Number one rule: don't come into contact with your forward self.
所以才需要这些屏障和防护衣
It's the whole point of these barriers and protective suits.
我们没有时间了
We don't have time.
你的粒子若是接触到
Well, if your particles come into contact...
会怎样
What?
全人类灭绝
Annihilation.
那就糟糕了 对吧
That would be bad, right?
走出气闸后 花点时间适应环境
When you exit the air lock, take a moment to orient yourself.
一切都会感觉很奇怪
Things will feel strange.
当你奔跑 风会从你后面吹来
When you run, the wind will be at your back.
当你碰到火 衣服上会结冰 因为热传导被逆转了
You encounter fire, ice will form on your clothes as the transfer of heat is reversed.
地心引力会是正常的 但周遭的世界将是逆转的
Gravity will feel normal but appear reversed for the world around you.
你的视觉和听觉会受到扭曲 这是正常的
You may experience distortions in your vision and hearing.
我不能保证你会有操控性
I can't vouch for the handling.
摩擦力和风阻都被逆转
Friction and wind resistance are reversed.
你也被逆转 但这世界并没有
You are inverted. The world is not.
收发器在公事箱上面吗
Was the transponder on the case?
我们把它给丢了
We've tossed that case.
我逆向时间移动 所以必须遵循这个准则
I'm moving backwards. It's the ball I have to follow.
把追踪器给我
Give me the reader.
好吧
Okay.
准备好了吗
You ready?
追踪中
标准标记
东西不在里面
The material's not in the case.
把演算机的其它部分带去震源
Get the other sections of the algorithm to the hypocenter.
他撒了谎 东西不在BMW上
He was lying. It wasn't in the BMW.
到底在哪里
So, where is it?
我看到交换过程
I saw the handoff.
你害我白白射伤她
You made me shoot her for nothing.
你倒是让我的脉搏飙到130 没有人做到这一点
You did get my pulse above 130, no one's done that before.
就连我老婆也没有
Not even my wife.
艾佛斯和他的小组留下来清理现场
You left Ives and his team a hell of a cleanup.
热传导被逆转
Heat transfer was reversed.
你可能是史上第一个 因为爆炸导致失温的案例
You might be the first case of hypothermia from a gasoline explosion in history.
我已经见怪不怪了
At this point, nothing surprises.
我们正在回奥斯陆
We're headed back to Oslo?
在路特速的货柜里
In a Rotas shipping container.
他拿到东西了 尼尔
He's got the material, Neil.
我双手奉上它
I handed it to him on a plate.
我警告过你
I warned you...
发生过的事已经发生了 我现在知道了
What's happened's happened. I get it now.
但我很难相信说话模棱两可的人
But it's hard to take things on trust from people speaking half-truths.
这么说不公平
That's not fair.
你在我们见面前就参一脚
You were a part of this before we met.
你替普莉亚工作
Were you working for Priya?
不是
No.
现在知道对你没啥好处
It can't possibly do you any good to know that right now.
等这一切过去 我们还活着 你也还在乎
When this is over, if we're still standing, and you still care,
我就告诉你我的人生故事
then you can hear my life story, okay?
很抱歉拖你下水
I'm sorry I involved you.
你得告诉我是怎么回事
You need to tell me what's going on.
尼尔知道的显然比我多
Apparently Neil here knows more about it than I do.
祝好运 老兄
Good luck, pal.
告诉凯特任何事 普莉亚就会认为她是风险
By telling Kat anything, we're compromising her in Priya's eyes.
普莉亚早就这么认为了
In Priya's eyes, she's already compromised.
她有权知道为何自己可能会死
She has the right to know why she might die.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
我们能帮你就不会
Not if we have something to say about it.
我们能帮你
And we do.
你是谁
Who are you?
先从简单的开始 每条物理定律
Let's start with the simple stuff. Every law of physics...
东西不在里面
The material's not in the case.
把演算机的其它部分带去震源
Get the other sections of the algorithm to the hypocenter.
你受伤了
You injured?
演算机是什么 尼尔
What's the algorithm, Neil?
钚241是九个部分的其中一个
那是以物体呈现的分子式 所以不会被复制或以语言传递
It's a formula rendered into physical form so it can't be copied or communicated.
那是只有一个功能的黑盒子
It's a black box with one function.
什么功能
Which is?
逆转时间 但不是逆转物体或人
Inversion. But not objects or peoples.
而是我们周遭的世界
The world around us.
我不懂
I don't understand.
当他们逆转更多物体的熵
As they invert the entropy of more and more objects,
向前和向后的时间 就会愈来愈纠结
the two directions of time are becoming more intertwined.
但由于世界基本上还是向前运作
But because the environment essentially flows in our direction...
我们就能掌控时间
we dominate.
其他人总是逆流泅泳 那才救了你的命
They're always swimming upstream.
就像是迎风撒尿
Pissing in the wind.
演算机能够改变风向
And the algorithm can change the direction of that wind.
它能逆转全世界的熵
It can invert the entropy of the world.
那会怎样
And if that happens?
游戏结束 能说得更清楚吗
"End of play." Can you be a little more precise?
曾经活过的每个人和一切 都会立刻毁灭 够清楚了吧
Everyone and everything that's ever lived, destroyed. Instantly.
你睡得越久 就会越快康复
The more you sleep, the faster you'll heal.
在货车上了
On a truck.
应该就快到了
Shouldn't be long now.
我一直在想 我们是他们的祖先
I've been thinking. We're their ancestors.
他们毁灭我们不也毁灭了自己
If they destroy us, won't that destroy them?
这就要提到祖父悖论
This brings us to the grandfather paradox.
什么
The what?
假如你回到过去把自己祖父杀掉
If you went back in time
答案是什么
What's the answer?
没有答案 这是悖论
There's no answer. It's a paradox.
但是在未来 当权者显然相信你能
But in the future, those in power clearly believe that you can
把你祖父踢下楼梯 挖出他的眼珠
kick grandpa down the stairs, gouge his eyes out,
切断他的喉咙 却没有任何后果
slit his throat, without consequence.
他们有可能对吗
Could they be right?
不重要 他们深信不疑
Doesn't matter. They believe it.
而且愿意毁灭我们
So they're willing to destroy us.
我要继续睡觉了
Can I go back to sleep now?
不行 我又想到另一件事
No. I thought of something else.
太好了
Great.
像这样逆转时间
This reversing the flow of time.
我们此刻身在此处 岂不代表从未发生
Doesn't us being here now mean it never happens?
因为我们阻止了他们
That we stop them?
乐观来说 我认为是对的
Optimistically, I'd say that's right.
悲观来说呢
Pessimistically?
在平行世界理论中 我们不可能知道
In a parallel worlds theory, we can't know the relationship
意识和多重现实的关系
between consciousness and multiple realities.
你开始头痛了吗
Does your head hurt yet?
当然
Yes.
试着睡觉吧
Try to sleep.
靠
Shit.
他们没载我们进去
They didn't take us inside.
该怎么办
What do we do?
我们从破口进去
We use the breach.
撞上去后趁乱行动 准备好
The chaos right after impact. Get ready.
她的伤好了吗
She healed enough?
不知道 我从来没做过这种事
I don't know. I've never done this before.
消防队来了 带凯特从破口进去
The fire crew's there.
你再带她进来
Then you bring her in.
你的伤怎样
How's your arm?
不太妙
Not good.
听到引擎爆炸后马上行动
We move as soon as we hear the engines.
-等等 -怎么了
- Hold on, hold on. - What?
你在流血
You're bleeding.
来 让我看看
All right, let me take a look at it.
好了吗
Ready?
在这儿等 我要进去
Wait here. I'm going in.
快啊
Come on!
快走
Go, go, go!
Go!
你明知是我从保险库出来 干嘛不说
You knew it was me coming out of that vault.
事实不会改变 我知道你不会有事
Thing's the same, I knew you'd be okay.
发生过的已经发生了
What's happened's happened.
我若先说 你又改变作法 谁知道会怎样
If I told you and you acted differently, who knows?
规定是不能说
The policy is to suppress.
谁规定的
Whose policy?
我们啊 朋友
Ours, my friend.
我们要拯救走向灭亡的世界
We're the people saving the world from what might've been.
凯特
Kat?
我在这儿
I'm here.
伤疤会很大 你不会有事
It'll be quite a scar. You'll be okay.
搞定了
Did it.
搞定了什么
You did what?
安德烈拿到演算机
Andrei has the algorithm.
你不知道他在哪里
You don't know where he is.
或哪个时空
Or when.
-把普莉亚带来奥斯陆 -为什么
- Get Priya here to Oslo. - Why?
若我不做点什么 两天后她就会告诉我钚241的事
If I don't do something, in two days, she tells me about the 241.
那是无法改变的
Nothing can change that.
等着瞧
We'll see.
把她带来
Just get her here.
你好 普莉亚
Hello, Priya.
怎么回事 尼尔呢
What's going on?
我做了什么
What did I do?
是你打算做什么 两天后你会派我把钚241
It's what you're going to do. In two days, you're gonna have me dangle plutonium-241
拿到世上最危险的军火商面前当钓饵
in front of the world's most dangerous arms dealer.
我想要知道原因
Now, I wanna know why.
你让萨托拿到钚241
You let Sator get hold of 241?
不 我让他拿到演算机
No, I let him get ahold of the algorithm.
告诉我实情 普莉亚
So, tell me about it, Priya.
那是独一无二的
It's... It's unique.
打造它的科学家自杀了 这样她就不会被迫打造另一台
The scientist who built it took her own life so she couldn't be forced to make another.
未来的科学家
A scientist in the future?
好几个世代以后
Generations from now.
她为什么必须自杀
Why does she have to kill herself?
你知道曼哈顿计划吗
You're familiar with the Manhattan Project?
第一次原子弹试爆前 欧本海默开始担心
As they approached the first atomic test,
想像她是那个世代的欧本海默
Think of our scientist as her generation's Oppenheimer.
她发明了逆转世界的方法
She devises a method for inverting the world,
但是坚信只要毁灭我们 也会毁灭他们自己
but becomes convinced that by destroying us, they're destroying themselves.
祖父悖论
The grandfather paradox.
但是和欧本海默不同 她坚决反抗
But, unlike Oppenheimer,
然后藏在她能想到最好的地方
and hiding them the best place she can think of.
过去 也就是现今
The past.
九个受到史上最严密保护的物质
Nine bombs. Nine sets of the most closely guarded materials in the history of the world.
最安全的隐藏处
The best hiding place possible.
核子安全厂房
Nuclear containment facilities.
萨托受到未来人资助 终其一生的任务
Sator's lifelong mission, financed and guided by the future, has been to
就是找到并组装演算机
find and reassemble the algorithm.
他们为何挑中他
Why do they choose him?
因为他刚好出现在对的地方
Because he was at the right place at the right time.
苏联解体的时候
The collapse of the Soviet Union.
核武史上最不安全的时刻
The most insecure moment in the history of nuclear weapons.
他有几个部分
How many sections does he have?
拿到钚241后 九个都有
After the 241, all nine.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
所以这次我们要采取不一样的行动
And that's why you're going to do things differently this time.
改变作法 好让凯萨琳不受伤
To change things?
那个宇宙若是存在
If that universe can exist...
也没有我们容身之处
we don't live in it.
总得试试看吧
Well, let's try.
你会警告我
You're going to warn me.
我不会 无知是我们的优势
No, I'm not. Ignorance is our ammunition.
拜托
Come on.
你若知道演算机是什么
If you had known what the algorithm was,
还会让它落在萨托手上
would you have let it fall into Sator's hands?
你希望萨托拿到最后一部分
You want Sator to get the last section.
这样他才会带来另外八个
That is the only way he'll bring together the other eight.
我应该偷走它
I was supposed to steal it...
然后弄丢它
then lose it?
任务达成
Mission accomplished.
你利用我
You used me.
就像你利用凯萨琳
As you used Katherine.
标准行动程序
Standard operating procedure.
你尽了你的职责
You've done your part.
我的职责
My part?
我是这项行动的主人翁
I'm the protagonist of this operation.
你只是其中一个
You... are a protagonist.
你自以为是拯救世界唯一的救世主
Did you think you were the only one capable of saving the world?
不是
No.
但我是 因为我还没告诉你
But I am.
你马上就会告诉我
You're about to.
才不会 那就让我们参一脚
No, I'm not. So, deal us in.
我们
"Us"?
为何又要把她拖下水
Why would you want to involve her again?
因为她能接近他
Because she can get close to him.
他还信任她吗
Does he still trust her?
他以为她死了 但他曾经信任她
He thinks she's dead.
现在轮到你了
And now, it's your turn.
就算你觉得她知道太多 还是得假设她逃过死劫
Assuming she makes it out alive,whether or not you feel she knows too much.
办不到
I can't.
如果你没有权力
If you don't have the authority,
那就让我和负责处理的人谈谈
then talk to whoever's in charge of loose ends.
我要你承诺
I need your word
她和她儿子的安全 普莉亚
that she and her son will be safe, Priya.
干我们这行承诺有什么用
What good is someone's word in our line of business?
他们会很安全
They'll be safe.
特隆赫姆外海有个集合点
There's a rally point offshore at Trondheim.
设法赶到那里
Get yourselves up there.
艾佛斯有一个小组准备逆转
Ives has a team ready to invert.
你有逆转门
You have a turnstile?
和我们试图摧毁的科技一模一样
The exact technology that we're trying to suppress.
以火攻火很危险
Fighting fire with fire's a treacherous business.
但是未来有一些人
But there are some people, in the future,
想要继续把演算机送回过去
who want to continue the algorithm's journey into the past.
你要知道 天能不是在过去建立
You see... Tenet wasn't founded in the past.
而是将在未来成立
It will be founded in the future.
还是不习惯鸟倒着飞
Can't get over the birds.
还好吧
How're you feeling?
告诉我你会杀了他
Tell me you're gonna kill him.
办不到
I can't.
为什么
Why not?
我打赌你一定杀过很多人
Bet you've probably killed a lot of people.
他有个失能开关
Not with a dead man's switch.
就是他戴的智慧手环
The fitness tracker he wears.
他一直在监控他的健康
He's obsessive about his health.
手环连结到一个开关
It'll be linked to a switch,
大概是一封电邮透露情报点的位置
probably a simple e-mail burst that reveals the location of the dead drop,
他心跳一停止就会起动
set to fire if his heart stops.
他的死会启动演算机
His death activates the algorithm.
他死了世界就会毁灭 没人敢杀他
He dies, the world ends. No one dares kill him.
不对 你想错了
No, you've missed the point.
他打算自我了结
He's intending to end his life.
为什么
Why?
他就快死了
He's dying.
无法治愈的胰脏癌
Inoperable pancreatic cancer.
他要把全世界当成陪葬品
And he's taking the world with him.
他若无法拥有 谁都不能
If he can't have her, no one can.
他能决定何时何处毁灭世界
He gets to choose the time and place for the end of the world.
他会选择哪个时刻
What moment? What does he choose?
你曾说某次度假让他觉得被爱
You told me about a holiday where you let him feel loved.
越南
Vietnam.
你说他消失不见 是哪一天
You said he vanished. What day?
我和麦斯上岸 他搭机飞走 但不知道是哪一天
I went ashore with Max and he flew off, but I don't know what day it was.
14号 10天前 他人在乌克兰
It was the 14th. Ten days ago.
你怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
重点是他不在游艇上 那是他的空档
The point is, he wasn't on his yacht, so that's his window.
回到那个黄金时刻 也是他生命的最后一刻
To go back to that golden moment and have it be his last.
每个人的最后一刻
Everyone's last.
我们得神不知鬼不觉 从情报点偷走演算机
We have to lift the algorithm from the dead drop
而且大家不必陪葬
And not the rest of us.
情报点在哪里
Where's the dead drop?
天机不可泄漏 朋友
Knowledge divided, my friend.
你不告诉我
You're not gonna tell me?
无知是我们的优势
Ignorance is our ammunition.
但我需要你回到游艇 凯特
But I need you back on that yacht, Kat.
为什么
Why?
你得阻止他自杀
You have to stop him killing himself
直到我们确定演算机不在情报点
until we know the algorithm is out of the dead drop.
要是我被逮到 我儿子会目睹一切
But if I'm caught there, my son sees.
若他时候到了 我不希望他死前看到这一幕
I don't want those moments to be full of anguish if they're gonna be his last.
不会的
They're not.
时间到了
It's time.
我们正在倒退回14号 但不知道情报点在哪里
We're working our way back to the 14th, but without knowing where the dead drop is,
我也没办法准备什么
there's only so much I can do to prepare.
你知道震源是什么吗
You know what a hypocenter is?
地下核武试爆的原爆点
It's ground zero for an underground nuclear test.
麦可寇斯比爵士告诉我 史托斯克12市14号有一场核爆
Sir Michael Crosby told me about a detonation in Stalsk-12 on the 14th.
情报点就在震源底下
The dead drop is at the bottom of the hypocenter.
核爆把演算机封在地底
That explosion seals up the algorithm.
我们最好在核爆前把它挖出来
Well, then we better pull it out of that hole before the bomb goes off, eh?
排队
Line it up.
向前走
Move forward.
下一个
Next.
排队
Line it up.
尼尔呢
Where's Neil?
他一定先过去了
He must've gone through already.
我没有说再见
I didn't get to say goodbye.
这就是再见 不是吗
This is goodbye, isn't it?
我很想说 你不必这么做
I'd like to say...that you don't have to do this
安德烈对我做过最坏的事 就是他向我提出条件
Kat...Worst thing Andrei ever did to me was that offer he made me.
我不再见儿子 他就放我走
Let me go if I agreed never to see my son again.
我大吼大叫 大飙脏话
I shouted and... swore.
但有一瞬间他从我表情看出
But he'd seen it on my face, just for an instant.
我在认真考虑
I considered it.
我不知道是因为我恨透他了
I don't know if I hate him more for what he's done,
或是因为他看穿了我
or because he knows that about me.
喔
Oh.
有机会救我儿子 你不了解那对一个母亲的意义
A chance to help save my child. You can't know what that means to a mother.
没错
No.
你曾经杀过你痛恨的人
You've killed people you've hated before.
通常不是出于私仇
It's not usually personal.
反正他快死了 也许并不算
Well, he's dying anyway. Maybe it doesn't even count.
每杀一个人都算
It always counts, Kat.
你不是去杀他 而是去阻止他
You're not there to kill him, you're the backstop.
若我们没偷走演算机 他自杀成功
If we don't lift that algorithm and he kills himself,
就会害死全人类
he takes us all with him.
遵守你的承诺 好吗
You just keep up your end, okay?
今天是14号
Today's the 14th.
西伯利亚外海 该行动了
Offshore of Siberia.
-谁能让我登上游艇  -我有最佳的人选
give you some time to get back into Vietnam. And who gets me on the yacht?
你一定会在某时某处受到威胁
There may be a time and place you feel threatened.
按下通话键 说出你的位置就挂断
Hit "talk," state your location, hang up.
谁会听到留言
Who gets the message?
后代的人
Posterity.
史托斯克12市
Stalsk-12.
一座隐匿的城市 什么事都有可能发生
Hidden from the world is a city where anything can happen.
就在今天  各位 10分钟后
And today, ladies and gents, for ten minutes,
一定会发生一件惊天大事
it most assuredly does.
你们被分成两队 展开时间钳形攻势
You've been divided into two teams for a temporal pincer movement.
我们是红队 顺着时间向前
We're Red Team, moving forward.
为了容易分辨 你们会配戴这些
In order to distinguish the teams, you'll wear these.
那边的朋友 由惠勒中校率领的蓝队逆转时间
Our friends over there, Blue Team, led by Commander Wheeler, are inverted.
为什么不让我们看到他们
Why don't they let us see them?
也许我们不会喜欢发生的事
Maybe we won't like what happened.
他们1小时后会听到同样的简报
One hour from now, they had this briefing.
然后会空降在震源上方的山脊
Then, were dropped on the ridge above the hypocenter,
尽量接近核爆发生的时间
as close in time to the detonation as possible.
他们的任务是清除现场
Their objectives were clearance and clarification.
这次简报有他们在未来的经验
Now, this briefing has the benefit of their experience.
两支队伍都有倒数码表
Both teams have countdown watches.
我们空降后从10倒数 一直到0的核爆发生
Ours counts down from ten, from landing to zero to the explosion.
-蓝队的时间被逆转 -大伙儿 向左看
- Blue Team is reversed. - Everybody, look to your left.
要是你到0还没到空降区 就别想活着离开
If you are not at the LZ at zero, you are not leaving.
了解吗
Do you understand?
空降后清除现场让蓝队安全撤退
We drop in, clear LZs for Blue Team evacuation.
然后一路挺进市区
We make our way into the city proper.
这些是废弃建筑物 但我们得知 某处有一道逆转门
These buildings are abandoned, but we learned there is a turnstile.
可能会遭到敌人攻击
Expect a bitemporal response.
会有逆转时间的弹炮吗
They'll have inverse ordnance?
逆转时间的 传统的
Inverse, conventional,
正常的敌人 逆转的敌人 什么都有
forward antagonists, inverted antagonists, they have it all.
城市另一边的地面隆起 一直到震源上方的山脊
On the other side of the city, the ground rises to the ridge above the hypocenter.
小分队会从市区走这条隧道 一直到震源的地底
A splinter unit will take this tunnel from the city to the floor of the hypocenter.
蓝队守住这里的入口
Blue Team located an entrance here.
这块岩石里的炸弹
The bomb is in this rock,
会在高处引爆造成山崩 封住山洞
high above, to trigger a collapse,
不用 炸弹会按照计划引爆
We don't. The explosion takes place as planned.
我们的任务就是拆除炸弹失败
Now, our job is to fail to defuse that bomb
好让小分队神不知鬼不觉完成任务
while the splinter unit achieves its task undetected.
什么任务
Which is?
这是机密 你不必知道
Need-to-know, and you don't.
还有别的蠢问题吗
Any other stupid questions?
很好 走吧 快去准备
Good. Well, let's go. Let's get ready.
我要参与第一波行动
I wanted to be on the first wave.
没有第一波行动 红队和蓝队同时展开行动
There is no first wave. Red Team and Blue Team operate simultaneously.
听好 你若拘泥于传统线性时间 就别上直升机
Look, don't get on the chopper if you can't stop thinking in linear terms.
你想加入成功得手的队伍吗
Now, you wanna be on the team that lifts the contents of the capsule?
当然想
Absolutely.
那就是我们俩
Yeah, that's us.
我们是小分队
We're splinter unit.
只有我们
Just us?
知道容器里装什么的人 不能离开战场
No one who knows the contents of that capsule can leave the field.
我们会自己搞定
I thought we'd manage ourselves.
甲板离水面有40尺 你下得去吗
It's 40 feet from the private deck to the water.
我发射信号弹前别让他死
Until you see my signal, you don't let him die.
30秒
Thirty seconds!
快上 快上
Go! Go! Go!
我们即将遭遇冲击波 抓紧了
We're coming in on a shockwave. Hang on, people.
站起来
On your feet!
那里
There!
夫人 我们以为您上岸了
Ma'am. We thought you'd gone ashore.
我偷溜回来给安德烈一个惊喜
Well, I snuck back to surprise Andrei.
老板走了耶
Oh, the boss left.
请萨托先生来这里找我 别告诉其他人
Well, have Mr. Sator find me here.
地雷
Mines!
他们说你上岸了
They told me you'd gone ashore.
他们说你飞走了
They told me you'd flown off.
我回来看你和麦斯
I came back to see you and Max.
麦斯跟安娜在岸上
Max is on shore with Anna.
我们吵过架 得好好谈谈
We need time, just you and me, after what happened.
我只是开玩笑 那是个蠢笑话
I was joking. It was a stupid joke.
你认为我是个坏妈妈
You think I'm a terrible mother.
我们都知道你比较讨厌我
We both know my opinion of you is higher than yours of me.
我希望我们的关系好一点
I want things to be better, Andrei.
找掩护
Take cover!
给我AT4反坦克火箭筒
Get me a goddamn AT4!
马上把他除掉
Take him out, now!
提供掩护
Provide some cover!
快点 快啊 快上
Move, move, move! Let's go!
快 快
Move, move, move!
惠勒
Wheeler!
快逃
Get outta there!
来啊
Come on!
艾佛斯
Ives!
小分队 这里
Splinter unit. Here.
今天的夕阳会很美
You know, it's going to be a beautiful sunset.
我会派人带麦斯回来 我们应该跟他有亲子时间
I'll get Max brought back. We should share the moment with him.
我替你倒杯酒
I'll make you a drink.
把我儿子带回游艇
Bring my son back to the boat.
没时间了 快走
We're runnin' out of time, let's go!
他们看到我们就完了
If they see us, it's all for nothing.
需要声东击西
We need a distraction.
安啦
Don't worry about that.
听我命令
On my mark!
用火箭筒炮轰基地
RPG, hit the base!
炮轰那栋建筑物
That building on my mark!
3、2
Three! Two!
1 开火
One! Fire!
开火
Fire!
快上
Move! Move!
没退路了 来吧
We're committed now. Come on.
那是什么
What's that?
我向中情局借来的
I borrowed it from the CIA.
是什么
What is it?
毁灭世界的方法
The way the world ends.
不是轰隆巨响 而是悄然一声
Not with a bang, but a whimper.
我不懂
I don't understand.
我吞下这个 万物都会消逝
When I take this, it's all over.
那就先别吞
Then don't take it yet.
为什么
Why not?
因为就快看到夕阳了
Because we have the sunset coming.
还剩下一点伏特加
And a little vodka left.
麦斯也很快就回来
And Max will be here soon.
他们说是你在岸上陪麦斯 不是安娜
They said they thought it was you, not Anna, ashore with Max.
只要你分得出来就好
So long as you can tell the difference.
我要办正事了 亲爱的
A moment's business, my love.
米耶 收到吗
Mahir, do you copy?
还不行 我重覆 还不行
Not clear. I repeat, not clear!
收到
Copy that.
我重覆 还不行
I repeat, not clear!
尼尔
Neil!
快上
Go!
炸弹威力不够把门炸开
We don't have anything big enough to blow this.
搜他身 看有没有手榴弹
Try him. See if he's got a grenade.
有吗
Anything?
没有
Nah, nothing.
过来看看 能不能撬开锁
Here, you try having a look. Can you pick it?
希望不能 那锁花了我很多钱
I hope not. I paid a lot for that lock.
喜欢我旅程的开始 还有你旅程的结束吗
How do you like where my journey began and yours ends?
核弹的辐射太强了
Little radioactive for my taste.
我的宿命和核弹息息相关
My fate was always bound up with radiation.
我们在最危险的地方干活
We'd work where no one else would.
我和魔鬼做了交易
I made a bargain with the devil.
金钱交换时间
Money for time.
我们出卖我们的未来
We sold our futures.
现在你要犯下足以毁灭世界的错误
And now you're about to make the same mistake for the entire world.
那不是错误 而是我交换的条件
It wasn't a mistake. I made the bargain I could.
你的回报是什么
What was yours?
你为了不解的使命而奋战
You fight for a cause you barely understand...
与你不信任的人合作 什么都没告诉他们
with people you trust so little, you've told them nothing.
我死了 世界也跟着我毁灭
When I die, the world dies with me.
你的知识也随着你消逝
And your knowledge dies with you,
一起被埋进坟里 就像一个无名的古埃及建筑工人
buried in a tomb like an anonymous Egyptian builder
被封在金字塔里以守住秘密
sealed in a pyramid to keep his secret.
你的信仰是盲目的 你是个疯子
Your faith is blind. You're a fanatic.
有什么比毁灭世界更疯狂
What's more fanatical than trying to destroy the world?
并不是 我在创造一个新世界
I'm not, I'm creating a new one.
某时某处 一个人在水晶塔中打开开关
Somewhere, sometime, a man in a crystalline tower throws a switch
就同时触发并避免了世界末日
and Armageddon is both triggered and avoided.
现在时间自己逆转方向
Now time itself switches direction.
我们沐浴在其中的阳光
The same sunshine we basked in
将温暖我们在未来世代的后裔
will warm the faces of our descendants generations to come.
他们为何要杀死我们
How could they wanna kill us?
因为他们的海水上涨 河流干枯
Because their oceans rose and their rivers ran dry.
你不明白吗  他们别无选择才会逆转时间
Don't you see? They have no choice but to turn back.
都是我们的错
We're responsible.
你知道了事实 还会阻止我吗
Knowing this, do you still want me to stop?
会 每个世代都努力设法存活
Yes. Each generation looks out for its own survival.
这就是他们在做的
That's exactly what they're doing.
但你不是 你是个叛徒
But not you. You're a traitor.
你没有自己的人生才想害死所有人
Bringing death to all, because you have no life
你儿子的生命不会
Not your son's.
我最大的罪过就是把儿子 带进我明知会灭亡的世界
My greatest sin was to bring a son into a world I knew was ending.
你觉得上帝会宽恕我吗
You think God will forgive me?
等等
Wait!
可恶
God...
掩护我
Cover me!
快上 快上
Go! Go! Go!
你不相信上帝或未来 或是在你经验之外的事
You don't believe in God, or a future, or anything outside of your own experience.
其它的才是信仰
The rest is belief.
而我没有信念
And I don't have it.
没有信念就不是人类 你只是个疯子
Without it, you're not human. You're just a madman.
或是一个神之类的
Or a god.
住手 天啊
Don't. Jesus.
我们的时间到了
Our time is up.
我会替你问候我老婆
I'll give your love to my wife.
你忘了 我还不认识她
You're forgetting. I haven't met her yet.
没错 你认识她以后她就死了
That's right. After you meet her, she dies.
那我就把我的爱给她
I'll just give her my love instead.
别这么做
Don't do...
瓦克夫
Volkov...
射爆他的头
别谈公事了 亲爱的
Enough business, my love.
你根本不知道我在说什么 对吧
You have no idea what I'm talking about, do you?
不过听起来很重要
But it sounds terribly important.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
你不热吗
Aren't you hot?
你在干嘛
What are you doing now?
防晒油挤得满地
I spilled sunscreen.
-又怎样  -甲板很滑
- So what? - Slippery!
过来吧
Just come here.
转过去 你会喜欢的
Turn over. You'll like it.
我做不到
I can't do this.
-我不能让你以为你赢了 -别破坏这一刻 凯特
- I can't let you think you've won. - Don't spoil this moment, Kat.
我不会让你进了坟墓 还以为会带我们一起陪葬
I'm not letting you go to your grave thinking we're coming with you.
你会孤独死去 安德烈
You're dying alone, Andrei.
快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on!
隧道封死 闸门关闭
Tunnel's sealed, gate's closed.
米耶 收到吗
Mahir, do you copy?
收到
Yeah.
先别行动 我重覆 别行动
Hold. I repeat, hold!
看着我的双眼
Look in my eyes.
你看到什么
Which do you see?
绝望或愤怒
Despair or anger?
我不是能给你爱的女人 虽然你伤了她的心
I'm not the woman who could find love for you even though you scarred her on the inside.
我是被你射伤 存心要报复的悍妇
I'm the vengeful bitch you scarred on the outside.
不
No!
惨了
Shit.
艾佛斯 她杀了他 收到吗  她杀死了他
Ives, she's killed him. Ives, do you copy? She's killed him.
她太早行动 杀死了他
She jumped the gun. She killed him.
快啊 他们到那里了吗
Come on, come on! Do you think they made it?
管它的
Ah, screw it.
凯特 你太早行动了
Kat! You jumped the gun!
我办不到 我不能让他觉得自己赢了才死
I couldn't do it. I couldn't let him die thinking he'd won.
我知道你会有办法
I knew you'd find a way.
等等 你有办法 我们不会死吧
Wait, you found a way, we're okay, right?
对 我有办法 保重
Yeah, found a way. Be safe.
我还以为你是逆转的
Thought you were inverted.
我在中间换了时间
Changed gears halfway.
看来你们这里需要帮忙
Looked like you needed help here.
这里 在下面时才需要帮忙
Here? We needed help down there.
你怎么把锁打开
How'd you get that lock open?
不是我 你的小队不是需要你
Wasn't me. Didn't your team need you?
下一次回去时再去带他们
I'll get 'em on the next pass.
好吗 艾佛斯
All right, Ives?
先等我喘口气
Once I've caught my breath.
看到这玩意的人都不能活着离开
No one who's seen this leaves the field.
好吧
All right.
我们把它藏起来
We hide it.
然后再自我了断
We end our lives.
这是唯一确定的方法
That's the only way to be sure.
至于何时自杀
As to when...
也许就让每个人自己决定
maybe that's every man's decision to make for himself.
你不杀我们
You're not gonna kill us?
我找到你们就会
If I ever find you, I will.
但你不会努力找吧
But you won't look too hard?
当然会
Yes, I will.
你不会回伦敦找凯特吧
You're not going back to London to check on Kat, are you?
不会 太危险了
No. It's far too dangerous.
远远看她也不会
Even from afar?
不会
Even from afar.
艾佛斯
Ives!
等等
Wait.
你真的要再回去
Are you really going back in?
只有我能及时把门打开 对吧
I'm the only one who could've got that door open in time, right, Ives?
你是最高竿的锁匠
Well, I don't know any locksmiths as good as you.
听到吗
See?
又是我在里面
It's me in there, again.
为了这项任务创造另一个过去
Weaving another past in the fabric of this mission.
尼尔 等等
Neil, wait!
我们才刚拯救世界
Just saved the world.
不能留下任何风险
Can't leave anything to chance.
但我们做法不同会改变什么吗
But can we change things if we do it differently?
发生过的已经发生了
"What's happened's happened."
这是对这个世界运作的信念
Which is an expression of faith in the mechanics of the world.
而不是袖手旁观的藉口
It's not an excuse to do nothing.
宿命
Fate?
随你怎么说
Call it what you want.
你会怎么说
What do you call it?
现实
Reality.
让我走吧
Now let me go.
你一直没说是谁找你来的 尼尔
Hey, you never did tell me who recruited you, Neil.
你到现在还没猜到
Haven't you guessed by now?
是你啊
You did.
只是跟你原来想的不一样
Only not when you thought.
你在过去有个未来
You have a future in the past.
对我来说是多年前 对你来说是多年后
Years ago for me. Years from now for you.
你认识我很多年了
You've known me for years?
对我来说 这是一段美好友情的结束
For me, I think this is the end of a beautiful friendship.
但对我来说 这只是开始
But for me, it's just the beginning.
我们一起干了一些事
We get up to some stuff.
你一定会喜欢 等着瞧
You're gonna love it. You'll see.
整项任务都是时间钳形攻势
This whole operation's a temporal pincer.
谁的任务
Whose?
你的
Yours!
你才完成一半
You're only halfway there.
我会在一开始见你 朋友
I'll see you at the beginning, friend.
我们拯救了可能走向灭亡的世界
We're the people saving the world from what might have been.
世人将永远不知道这件事
World will never know what could've happened.
就算知道也不会在乎
And even if they did, they wouldn't care.
因为没人在乎没引爆的炸弹
'Cause no one cares about the bomb that didn't go off.
坎农街3号
只有拯救世界的人才知道
Only the one that did.
在孩子出来前动手
Do it before the boy comes out.
这算是慈悲 你答应过我
That's your idea of mercy? You gave me your word.
我当时也告诉你要付出代价
And I told you then what it would be worth.
这里 就在今天
Here, today.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
坎农街 下午3点 大概没什么
Cannon Place, 3:00. Probably nothing, I'm...
后代
Posterity.
坎农街 下午3点 大概没什么
Cannon Place, 3:00. Probably nothing, I'm...
我跟你说过 你得开始以不同角度看这世界
I told you you'd have to start looking differently at the world.
-我必须清理善后 -那从来都不是你的责任
- I have to tie up the loose ends. - That was never your job.
那是谁的
Then whose was it?
我的
Mine.
我发现我不替你工作 我们一直都在替我工作
I realized I wasn't working for you. We've both been working for me.
我才是主人翁
I'm the protagonist.
那你最好赶快清理善后
Then you'd better tie up those loose ends.
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
那是一枚没有引爆的炸弹
It's the bomb that didn't go off.
没人知道的危机确实存在
The danger no one knew was real.
那枚炸弹拥有真正改变世界的力量
That's the bomb with the real power to change the world.